Mat Gargano

(917) 734-0673 - mgargano@gmail.com - matgargano.com

Veteran full stack web application architect experienced in application design and development, data modeling, cross-browser user interface design, translating business requirements to technical specifications, project management and team building.

Professional Experience

Lead Developer (Director of Web Engineering), Morgan & Morgan, P.A Brooklyn, NY 11/2015 – Present

- Led team of 5 in the modernizing of legacy web applications.
- Application development using Laravel, Lumen, WordPress and Vue.js.
- Built out RESTful microservices to ensure critical uptime.
- Implemented Timber separating the controller and view for WordPress enhancing the separation of concerns while taking advantage of WordPress' strong CMS functionality.
- Handled devops for hosting over 15 sites and applications.
- Connected applications to HubSpot, Salesforce and other third party services.

Senior Technical Lead, Story Worldwide 4/2015 - 11/2015

New York, NY

- Architect and led development of web applications and sites for Beechnut, Suave, Country Crock, I Can't Believe It's Not Butter and other Unilever brands.
- Handle strategy for pitch development ideation and conceptualization.
- Mentor developers while hands on developing.
- Introduced modern workflow to development model.

Lead Web Application Developer, Voce Communications 7/2013 – 4/2015

New York, NY

- Enterprise-scale WordPress and mobile architecture and development taking advantage of Composer, Capistrano, Grunt, and Capistrano to streamline build process.
- Led team of developers as well as hands on coding every day.
- Introduced Unit Testing to WordPress plugins.

Lead Web Developer, Popdust 6/2012 - 7/2013

New York, NY

- Scalable and reusable full-stack (PHP5, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, LESS, SASS) development using the WordPress as a framework.
- RESTful service development using Laravel framework with Redis to abstract high-scale voting application layer away from WordPress/MySQL.
- Migrated Popdust.com to new technology, scaled to handle enormous growth as Popdust increased its reach globally.

Web Developer, The Harry Fox Agency 1/2011 – 6/2012

New York, NY

Introduced SoA to modernize legacy systems built on top of AS400/RPG and DB2/Java.

Mat Gargano

(917) 734-0673 - mgargano@gmail.com - matgargano.com

Vice President, Bank of America Merrill Lynch 12/2009 – 1/2011

New York, NY

- Served as project manager for migration of Excel based inquiry log to third party application driven system. Duties included documenting business logic, user interface, user experience requirements along with user acceptance testing.
- Wrote VBA scripts that digested complex Excel workbooks and distilled information for presentation to executive team.

RFP Database Manager, OppenheimerFunds, Inc. 3/2006 – 12/2009

New York, NY

• Developed PHP/MySQL based intake system to manage RFP submission process that provided internal clients a resource to create and track requests from inception to completion.

Open Source Community Contributions

As an active member of the open source community I have contributed the following projects:

- Tutorial, Unit Testing for WordPress Parts 1, 2 and 3 available at voceplatforms.com/2014/09/unit-testing-for-wordpress-part-1-the-setup/.
- Plugins available in the WordPress Plugin Repository including Easy Weather Widget,
 Super Recent Posts Widget, Easy Nag Popup
- Core contributions in Timber plugin for WordPress

Technologies

Operating Systems: OS X, *nix, MS Windows XP/Vista/7/8

Development: PHP (WordPress, Laravel, Composer), MySQL, JavaScript

HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, git, bash, Vagrant, PHPUnit, nginx, apache, memcache, redis, varnish, ansible, xdebug

Code Repositories: github.com/matgargano

packagist.org/users/mgargano profiles.wordpress.org/matstars

Education

Binghamton University, School of Management, New York, NY Master of Business Administration (MBA) August 2008

Binghamton University, School of Management, New York, NY Bachelor of Science, Management Information Systems

May 2004

References Furnished Upon Request